Guide to the Yale Debate Association Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale Debate Association records
1947-2008
RU 75
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
10
(22 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, budget and accounting records, rosters, memoranda, photographs and general administrative records concerning the activities of Rollin G. Osterweis as director of the Yale Debate Association.
Yale Debate Association
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Arrangement
The records are aranged in two series: I. Correspondence, 1948-1974. II. Subject Files, 1948-1980; and subsequent accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale Debate Association was founded in 1908.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, annual reports, budget and accounting records, rosters, memoranda, photographs and general administrative records concerning the activities of Rollin G. Osterweis as director of the Yale Debate Association.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Debates and debating; Osterweis, Rollin G. (Rollin Gustav), 1907-1982; Yale Debate Association; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, 1948-1974; Series I
  - 1948-1949
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - D-G (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - H (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - I-N (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - O-R (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - St-T (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - U-Z (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1949-1950
    - A-B (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - C-D (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - E-H (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - I-N (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - P-V (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - W-Z (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1950-1951
    - A-C (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - D-H (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - K-N (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - P-Z (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1951-1952
    - A-B (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - C-D (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - E-H (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - I-N (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - P-Z (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1952-1953
    - A-C (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - D-K (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - L-S (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - T-Z (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - 1953-1954
    - A-B (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - C-H (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - I-Z (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - 1954-1955
    - A-C (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - D-G (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - H-M (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - N-R (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - S-Z (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - 1955-1956
    - A-C (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - D-H (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - I-Z (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - 1956-1957
    - A-D (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - E-I (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - J-Z (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - 1957-1958
    - A-P (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - H-N (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - P-Z (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - 1958-1959
    - A-C (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - D-M (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - N-P (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - R-Z (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - 1959-1960
    - A-C (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - D-H (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - L -R (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - S-Z (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - 1960-1961
    - A-C (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - D-K (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - M-Z (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - 1961-1962
    - A-G (Box 9, Folder 57)
    - H-L (Box 9, Folder 58)
    - M-P (Box 9, Folder 59)
    - R-Z (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - 1962-1963
    - A-C (Box 9, Folder 61)
    - D-G (Box 9, Folder 62)
    - H-M (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - N-P (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - R-Z (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - 1963-1964
    - A-C (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - D-J (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - K-P (Box 10, Folder 68)
    - R-Z (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - 1964-1965
    - A-F (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - G-N (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - P-Z (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - 1965-1966
    - A-D (Box 11, Folder 73)
    - E-P (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - R-Z (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - 1966-1967
    - A-D (Box 12, Folder 76)
    - E-P (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - R-Z (Box 12, Folder 78)
  - 1967-1968
    - A-D (Box 12, Folder 79)
    - E-N (Box 12, Folder 80)
    - P-Z (Box 12, Folder 81)
  - 1968-1969
    - A-J (Box 13, Folder 82)
    - L-Z (Box 13, Folder 83)
  - 1969-1970
    - A-C (Box 13, Folder 84)
    - D-M (Box 13, Folder 85)
    - N-Z (Box 13, Folder 86)
  - 1970-1971
    - A-L (Box 13, Folder 87)
    - M-Z (Box 13, Folder 88)
  - 1971-1972
    - A-M (Box 14, Folder 89)
    - N-Z (Box 14, Folder 90)
  - 1972-1973
    - A-N (Box 14, Folder 91)
    - P-Z (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - 1973-1974
    - A-N (Box 14, Folder 93)
    - N-Z (Box 14, Folder 94)
- Subject files, 1948-1980; Series II
  - Accounts
    - 1950-1958 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - 1959-1965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 1969-1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Debate Budget Book
    - 1948-1955 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - 1955-1961 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - 1961-1967 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - 1967-1972 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Debating, general
    - A - D, 1948 June - 1956 September (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - E - P, 1948 June - 1956 September (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - R - Z, 1948 June - 1956 September (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - History of the Harvard-Princeton-Yale Triangulars 1909-1959'', undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Ivy League Debate Conference, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Memorandum to the Dean of Yale Collegeregarding the Debating and Public SpeakingProgram at Yale, 1948 June 18 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Osterweis, Rollin G, Biography; corrected and final, 1980 September (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Permanent Memoranda
    - Yale Forensics A - F, 1956-1967 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Yale Forensics G - Z, 1956-1967 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Rosters, 1951-1953 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - The Yale Forensic program, 1956-1973 (Box 17, Folder 33)
- Photographs of the Yale Debate Association, 1947-1975; Accession 2002-A-125
  - Photographs, 1947-1975 (Box 1)
- Photographs and memorabilia, 1948-2008; Accession 2009-A-085
  - Manuscript (unpublished) of Rollin Osterweis, "American Oratory in Historical Perspective", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Obituary and newsclippings re: documentary "Freedom to Speak" about Rollin Osterweis (1983), 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale Debate Society group photographs
    - 1948-1949 (Bunden, Buckley, hadley, Osterweis, Shapiro, Looper, Chatiman?) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1952-1953 (Schnell, Kohmeyer, Osterweis, Tullis, Meese, Lowell) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yale vs. Columbia debate poster, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "A Tribute to Rollin G. Osterweis", 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorial service leaflet for Rollin Gustav Osterweis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Centennial reunion of the Yale Debate Association program of events, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale Debate Association centennial roster of attendees, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Constitution of the Yale Inter-College Debate League, 1952 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 77th Triangular Debate Championship Gavel, 1968 (Box 2)
- Yale Debate Association memorabilia, circa 1960-1974; Accession 2009-A-171
  - Basic Principles of Speech, undated (Box 1)
  - Speaker and Gavel, 1970 November (Box 1)
  - The Guide to North American Platform Debate, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Manual for Debate, perpared by the Intercollege Debate League, 1960 (Box 1)
  - photocopied article from The Gavel written by Rollin Osterweis, undated (Box 1)
- Scrapbook documenting Rollin Osterweis and the Yale Debate Association, 1974-1978; Accession 2010-A-078
  - Scrapbook documenting Rollin Osterweis and the Yale Debate Association, 1974-1978 (Box 1)